Records of the John Frost Library Collection RG.38.0
New York University Archives
Records of the John Frost Library Collection
1936-1975
New York University Archives
Frost, John Eldridge, 1917-1992
RG.38.0
6.25 Linear Feet (5 manuscript boxes)
The John Frost Library collection contains the administrative files of John Frost, who served as head librarian of the Gould Memorial Library at the University Heights campus between 1955-1972 and as a member of the library faculty from 1972-1982. The collection contains administrative files, including correspondence, committee meeting minutes, reports, publications and library floor plans.
Access Restrictions
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials.
Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files restricted under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted.
Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Historical/Biographical Note
John Eldridge Frost, clergyman, genealogist, and librarian at New York University, was born in Eliot, Maine, on January 13, 1917. He received a B.A. degree in Sacred Theology from Berkeley Divinity School at Yale University in 1941; a B.S. degree in library science from Columbia University in 1948; an M.A. degree from the University of New Hampshire in 1948; and a Ph.D. from New York University in 1953.
In 1942, he was ordained in the Episcopalian Church and served at the Church of the Advent in Westbury, New York; St. Mary's Chapel in Carle Place, New York; and All Saints Church in Worcester, Massachusetts. Frost was a chaplain in the Navy during World War II in 1945 and 1946.
While completing his Ph.D. at NYU, Frost served as an assistant librarian for the Washington Square College of Arts and Sciences. From 1955 to 1972, Frost held the position of head librarian at Gould Memorial Library, which was the main library in the University Heights campus in the Bronx. From 1972 to 1982, Frost was a member of the NYU library faculty.
In addition to his work as a librarian, Frost was a prominent genealogist and the author of The Nicholas Frost Family, Colonial Village, Sarah Orne Jewett and Maine Genealogy. He also authored and edited Maine Probate Abstracts, 2nd volume, 1991.
Dr. Frost was a long time member of the American Library Association, the Newcomen Society of England, and the Maine Historical Society, and was trustee and founder of the Gundalow Club, which was devoted to New England maritime history.
John Eldridge Frost died at the age of 75 on July 23, 1992, in York, Maine.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains administrative files, including correspondence, committee meeting minutes, reports, publications and library floor plans collected by John Eldridge Frost. The materials date from his time as head librarian of the Gould Memorial Library as well as his subsequent library faculty position at Washington Square College from 1972 onward. A portion of this collection contains documents regarding the construction, planning and dedication of Elmer Holmes Bobst Library on the Washington Square campus.
Separated Materials
Book plates, slides, photographs, and a number of publications have been separated from this collection. A collection of book plates have been integrated into our memorabilia collection. Slides and photographs depicting the library and NYU Professor Oscar Cargill have been transferred to our photograph collection. Publications, including books, newsletters, and journals have been integrated into the Bobst Main Collection.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically. The files are grouped into 3 series:
Missing Title
Series I: Library Administration
Series II: Bobst Library
Series III: Floor Plans
Series IV: Miscellaneous Publications
The folders are arranged alphabetically within each series. This collection consists of four series:
Correspondence.; Clippings (information artifacts); Publications (documents); Memorandums.; Floor plans.; Washington Square College |x Administration.; Elmer Holmes Bobst Library; New York University. University Heights; New York University. Office of Library Administration; New York University. Libraries
- Series I: Library Administration
  Scope and Content
  This series contains subject files which include correspondence, committee meeting minutes and memos, and policy guides relating to Library administrative policies and procedures. It also contains documents relating to special collections which were donated to the NYU libraries.
  - American Literature Collection, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - An Imperative Partnership: The Responsibilities & Implications of a Cooperative Program of Graduate Education for Business, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Archives, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arnold Library, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Beiman, Alan M. Memorial Collection, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Oscar Cargill Memorial Collection, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clubs, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Committees, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Files (restricted), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Frost, 1951-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fales Collection, 1959-1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Final Report of the Directing Committee of the New General Program, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Gallatin Papers, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Gifts, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Gifts & Endowment Record, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Gould Memorial Library, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration - Proposal for New Building, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Students Organization, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Guide to the Education Reading Room, 1952-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Guide to the Indexes & Abstracts in the Education Library, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Guide to the General University Library, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Guide to Research Sources in the Social Sciences, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Guides to the Services of the Library, 1936; undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Index to Early American Periodical Literature, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Items Related to Acquisition of Items, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Music Library, 1952-1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - NYU Library Manual of Office Procedures, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Press Clippings - Articles, 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Special Collections, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Various Collections (Xeroxed from cards), undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Series II: Bobst Library
  This series contains correspondence, committee meeting minutes and memos, news clippings, and other documents pertaining to the planning, construction and dedication of Bobst library.
  - Bobst Archives, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bobst Clipping File, 1962-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bobst Dedication - 1, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bobst Dedication - 2, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bobst Dedication - 3, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bobst Dedication - Enabling letters & Committee memos, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bobst Dedication - Expenses, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bobst Dedication - Invitation Lists, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bobst Dedication - November 2, 1972 meeting, 1972 November (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bobst Library - Miscellaneous, 1960-1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bobst Library - Miscellaneous, 1945-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bobst Library - Press Clippings, 1949; 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Bobst Specification Reports, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bobst Staff Bulletin, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dedication of Bobst Library - Documents and Comments, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Committee Meetings, 1964-1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Library Clippings, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - NYU - Libraries - Bobst, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Press Clippings (laminated), 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Programming Committee for the New General University Library, 1959-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Programming Committee, 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Two Bobst Library scarves in boxes wrapped in red paper with silver Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 10th anniversary stickers, undated (Box Shared University Archives 041)
- Series III: Floor Plans
  - 100 Washington Square East; Basement, 1st, 2nd Floor Plans, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Basement Floor Plan, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Basement Floor Plan - 100 Washington Square East, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bobst Library Floor Plans, 1972 July (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bobst Library - Mezzanine, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Main Stacks - Basement, 1936-1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Proposed Arrangement of Metal Bookstacks: Main Building (?) Basement, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Publications
  This series contains various small bound publications on varying topics.
  - Ebony Patriots, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Report: Reader's Division of the Washington Square LIbrary, by Edward C. Nelson, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Kaplan Diary, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Libraries of New York University, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Washington Square College, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Washington Square College - 2, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 16)